Guide to the Mary Duke Biddle Trent Semans Papers, 1947-1989 UA.29.02.0222
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Mary Duke Biddle Trent Semans papers
1947-1989
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Semans, Mary Duke Biddle Trent
UA.29.02.0222
2.0 Linear Feet
Mary Duke Biddle Trent Semans attended Duke University and graduated in the class of 1939. She later became a philanthropist and Duke trustee. This collection contains printed matter, photographs, clippings, speeches and other memorabilia relating to Semans' time as trustee, her affiliation with the British American Festival of 1984, and other Duke related activities and events.
Access Restrictions
Records of the University's Board of Trustees which have been in existence for at least fifty years are available for scholarly research with the permission of the University Archivist. Access to records which have been in existence for less than fifty years shall be granted only by special permission, in writing, from the Board of Trustees.
Provenance
The Mary Duke Biddle Trent Semans Papers were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1983.
Biographical Note
Mary Duke Biddle Trent Semans was born in 1920, and attended Duke University, graduating in 1939. She became a philanthropist and supporter of the arts, a trustee of Duke University and of the Duke Endowment, as well as vice-chairperson of the Mary Duke Biddle Foundation.
Collection Overview
This collection contains printed matter, photographs, clippings, speeches and other memorabilia relating to Semans' time as a Duke University trustee, her affiliation with the British American Festival of 1984, and other Duke-related activities and events.
Duke files include reports, programs, addresses and printed ephemera pertaining to matters and events at Duke University. These materials reflect Semans' activities as a university trustee as well as her support for the arts at Duke. These papers also include the transcript of a discussion on race relations at Duke and the takeover of the Allen Building from 1969, as well as minutes from the University Center Committee, the report of the Special Committee on the Functions and Organization of the Board of Trustees, and a summary report of the B.N. Duke Leadership Program.
These materials also include reports on fund raising at Duke and several reports that address salary levels and other issues faced by Duke faculty women and Semans' speech (with slides) given at the 100th Celebration of Duke Memorial United Methodist Church in 1986.
The British American Festival scrapbook contains clippings, correspondence and color snapshots relating to the 1984 North Carolina British-American Festival. There is also a a cassette tape of a recorded interview with Ian Hamilton, who composed "Raleigh's Dream" for the festival.
Oversize folders contain a newsletter from the Duke Class of 1939, Robert Ward's musical score for Music for a Great Occasion for Terry Sanford's inauguration, as well as chapel architectural drawings.
Related Materials
Papers of the Semans Family, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Events Reference Collection, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Board of Trustees Records, University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Scrapbooks; Audiocassettes; Duke Memorial United Methodist Church (Durham, N.C.); Duke University -- History -- 20th century; Duke University. Board of Trustees; British American Festival (1984: Durham, N.C.)
- Duke files, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Duke files, 1955-1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Duke files, 1962-1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Duke files, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Duke files, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Duke files, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Duke files, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Duke files, 1973-1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Duke files, 1983-1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Duke files, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Duke files, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Duke files, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Duke files: Items Separated, 1972, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Board of Trustees materials restricted until 2023.
- Christmas cards, 1960, 1962, 1965, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- British American Festival scrapbook (Box 2, Folder 4-13)
- British American Festival: Raleigh's Dream Composer Commentary I. Hamilton audiocassette, June 1984 (Box 1, Audio-cassette UA29020222-CS-01)
- Oversized items (Oversize-folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes: (1) Blueprint, Duke Chapel accessibility study for physically handicapped, 22 August 1977, (2) Duke University newsletter Class of 1939, January 1966, and (3) Ward, Robert, Music for a Great Occasion commissioned by Dr. and Mrs. James Semans for the Inauguration of Terry Sanford, fifth President of Duke University.